<resources>
    <string name="app_name">The New Coffee App</string>
    <string name="hario_v60">Hario V60</string>
    <string name="aeropress">Aeropress</string>
    <string name="french_press">French Press</string>
    <string name="iced_coffee">Iced Coffee</string>
    <string name="coffee_tips">Coffee Tips</string>
    <string name="calculator">Calculator</string>
    <string name="water_in_grams">Enter water in grams</string>
    <string name="coffee_in_grams">Enter coffee in grams</string>
    <string name="v60_description">The Hario V60 is a Pour over coffee brewer</string>

    <string name="v60_recipe"> \nThe Hario V60 is a pour-over brewer which means that water is poured over the water and the water travels through the bed of coffee with the help of gravity.
        \n\nRecommended dose:
        \n60 grams of coffee to 1000g (1L) of water.
        \nFor a half liter brew, you would use 30g of coffee and 500g of water.
        \n\nSteps: \n1. First we boil the water, measure and grind our beans and put the filter in the V60.
        \n\n2. Wet the filter with the warm water and discard it.
        \n\n3. Now we bloom the coffee by wetting all the coffee with 3:1 ratio grams of water to grams of coffee.
        \n\n4. The coffee blooms for 45 seconds to allow it to release CO2 gas trapped by the roasting process and release the flavor of the beans.
        \n\n5. Pour water in circles starting from the center and out, and then inwards spiral, and repeat until 350g of water has been poured.
        \n\n6. Once we reach about 3/4 of the total water, we wait for the coffee bed to lower (about 30s) and we pour water until we reach our target water weight.
        \n\n7. Quick stir once to the right and once to the left.
        \n\n8. Let the coffee drain while we move the V60 carefully in circles to get an even extraction.
        \n\n9. Remove the V60 filter holder and stir the coffee with a wooden spoon before pouring into cups.
        \n\n10. Serve the coffee and enjoy your fresh brew!
        \n\n
        \n\n
        \n\n
    </string>
</resources>